翻譯: vince 奇跡道長 Jamie
嗨 我是Michael Henry
Hi, I'm Michael Henry.
我曾是新聞4臺的王牌主播
I was lead anchor of the
五年前我離開了
Channel 4 news until I left five years ago.
好的一面是
The great thing is,
校對: 不賣萌斯基
我有更多的時間陪伴我家人
I've been able to spend more time with my family.
爸 你別亂動嘛
Dad, you're moving too much.
我又要重新對焦了
I've got to zoom out and start again.
后期: 怪查理
親愛的 你就算站對街拍我
Honey, you could shoot me from across the street.
也沒什么區別啊
It wouldn't make a difference.
你要是給我個有防抖功能的手機就有了
Maybe if you had gotten me a phone with an image stabilizer.
壓制: ＢＢ
沒錯 那就沒問題了
That would cure it.
拜托 輪到誰來擺餐桌了
Come on, people. Whose turn is it to set the table?
抱歉 我被學校永遠開不完的會議拖住了
Sorry, I was stuck at this never-ending staff meeting at school.
哦  意大利面
Ooh, pasta.
是 我放了兩份甘藍在里面 你肯定吃不出
Yeah, I put two things of kale in it, but you'd never know.
- 爸 今天吃什么 - Eve 去把桌子收拾了
- Hey, Dad. What do we got? - Eve, set the table.
- 甘藍 兩份甘藍 - 不許站著吃
- Kale. Two things of kale. - No standing and eating.
這種站著吃的習慣一定得改掉
This standing and eating thing has got to stop.
這個家正在陷入一個危險的深淵
This family's going down a dangerous rabbit hole.
首先我們不溝通了 下一秒
First we stop connecting, then next thing you
就在橋下互相幫對方綁手臂吸毒
know, we're under a bridge, tying each other off.
這招你怎么知道的
How do you know that move?
在遇到你之前我也有過去的 Annie
I had a past before you, Annie.
- 嗨 爸爸 - 好吧
- Hey, Dad. - Okay.
- 媽 蒜蓉面包 扔給我 - 不 別用扔的 不許扔
- Mom, garlic bread, hit me. - No, don't hit him. Don't hit him.
- 帥 - 好吧
- Nice! - Okay.
- 掉了我也吃 - 真的嗎
- I'm still eating it. - Really?
那就有個飯桌 我正看著它呢
There's a dining room table right there. I'm looking at it.
- 就在那兒 - 蠢蛋們 你們好
- I'm looking at it right there. - What up, fools?
別放甘藍了 知道你是白人啦
Enough with the kale. We get it: You're white.
你能多穿點么 你嚇著孩子了
Will you put those things away? You're scaring the kids.
- 嗨 Leigh姑姑 - 天啊
- 'Sup, Aunt Leigh? - Oh, my god.
這頓飯真棒 爸爸 又是一場大勝
Amazing meal, Dad. Another triumph.
Leigh姑姑 我們走吧
Let's go, Aunt Leigh.
別叫我姑姑 今晚我們是姐妹
Stop calling me Aunt Leigh. Tonight we're sisters.
我們原來的計劃呢 我們一起去吃晚飯
What about the plan? We were gonna have dinner,
吃點冰凍酸奶 或者再玩玩樹葉大戰
then go get frozen yogurt, and maybe have a leaf fight.
某種桌游
- 樹葉大戰 - 或者其他啥的
- A leaf fight? - Or something.
你說的冰凍酸奶不是真的冰凍的酸奶嗎
Do you know that frozen yogurt isn't actually frozen yogurt?
對 那只是動物明膠粉混上玉米糖漿
Yeah, it's just powdered animal gelatin and corn syrup.
你想對你家人做什么啊 Mike
What are you trying to do to your family, Mike?
反正你們要在十點半前回家
Just be home by 10:30.
- 就這樣了嗎 - 嗯 再見啦
- That's it? We're done? - Yep. Later.
至少還有我倆一起吃飯
Well, at least you and me can have a meal together.
我已經吃完了
I'm already done.
又 見 彩 虹
第一季  第一集
電波誠譯
我怎么形容我爸爸呢
How would I describe Dad?
他是賓夕法尼亞人 沒自己想的那么風趣
He's from Pennsylvania, not as funny as he thinks he is.
他戴帽子的方式就像是從商店的架子上
He wears hats like they just fell off a shelf
以各種姿勢掉在他頭上 不管多難看
in a store and whatever insane way it lands on his head,
他也都不整整
he just keeps it like that.
20年了 他把一切都傾注在工作上
For 20 years, he's poured everything he had into work.
現在他把一切都傾注在我們身上 好棒哦
Now he pours it all into us. Yay!
嘿 起床啦 起床啦
Hello! Wake up! Wake up!
起床啦 起床啦 別逼我撓你們啊
Wake up! Wake up! Wake up! Don't make me be a tickle bear.
- 走開啦 - 起床啦 起床啦 起床啦
- Go away! - Wake up! Wake up! Wake up!
只有一種方法能讓我住嘴
There's only one way to get me to stop.
醒醒 醒醒 Kevin小寶貝
Wakey, wakey, Kevin Bac-ey!
你永遠不用叫我起床好么 爸爸
You never had to drag me out of bed, Dad.
- 這些小孩真沒職業道德 - 大學輟學生如是說
- These kids have no work ethic. - Said the college drop-out.
我沒從大學輟學
I didn't drop out of college.
我選擇離開 這樣我就能專心于我熱愛的事
I opted out so I could focus on my passion:
開拓搜索引擎新世界
Reimagining the search engine.
勒布朗高中就參加NBA了
Lebron went pro out of high school.
我為啥要等到22歲才掙我的第一個一百萬
Why should I have to wait until I'm 22 to make my first million?
即使要在我弟弟房間里掙
Even if I have to do it in my little brother's room.
到處都是樂高積木 他都沒拼清楚
Legos everywhere. They're not even put together right.
看看這個拖船 什么玩意嘛
How is this a tug boat? Seriously.
這孩子真壯 跟獾一樣
Ah, this kid is strong. He's badger-strong.
我上高中英語之前要改30首詩
I've got 30 poems to grade before senior English.
- 詩怎么評分的啊 - 超嚴厲
- How do you grade poetry? - Harshly.
這個世界不需要爛詩了 我就是那個防詩墻
The world doesn't need more bad poetry, Mike. I am the firewall.
你可以走了啦 我會送孩子去學校的
Why don't you get out of here? I'll take the kids to school.
好 Eve第一節課有生物考試 別遲到了
Okay, Eve's got a Bio test first period. Don't be late.
你為什么非要在我學校教書
Why do you have to teach at my school?
- 你干嘛非要來我教書的學校上學 - 你就穿這個
- Why do you have to go to my school? - Are you wearing that?
我們要開磨冰機去學校嗎
What, are we driving a Zamboni to school?
你怎么打我這個病人啊
how can you hit a man in my condition?
拍好了么 多謝支持
Got it? Thanks.
你們周末想花一天去摘蘋果嘛
Hey, you guys want to go apple picking this weekend for the day?
不 我打算花五分鐘去超市買蘋果
No, I want to go to key foods for five minutes.
5點新聞主播 我們愛你哦
Yo, 5:00 news! We love you, bro!
謝了 瞧我這一手
Thanks, man. And thanks for that.
Mike Henry 全世界最受愛戴的主播
Mike Henry, world's most beloved man.
所有人都愛死你了
There's no one who doesn't love you.
- Harris 你最近怎么樣 - 還好吧
- Harris, how you been? - All right.
- 長高了嘛 Graham - 嘿 Harris
- Getting tall, Graham. - Hey, Harris.
嗨 Eve 衣服不錯嘛 最近在油井干活嗎
Hey, Eve. That's a nice jacket. What, you working on an oil rig?
- 哈 - 我昨晚看了新聞直播
- Ha. - I saw the newscast last night.
你認真的么
Are you serious?
快餐食品安全的又一個恐怖揭秘
Another scare piece on the dangers of fast food?
公眾早被警告過了 他們才不在乎
The public's been warned, Harris. They don't care.
- 不管孩子嗎 - 這是紐約 還能發生什么
- What about the kids? - It's New York. What could happen?
你知道你哪里得改改嗎
You know what else you've got to change?
Linda節目最后的那個標語 "尋找快樂"
Linda's new sign-off. I mean, "Find your happy"?
我們以前還深入黑幫組織呢
We used to infiltrate gangs.
我曾扶著攝影師的脖子一小時以免他流血死亡
I held a cameraman's neck for an hour so he wouldn't bleed out.
我記得 你靠這個得了你第四個艾美獎
I remember. You won your fourth Emmy for that.
嗨 Mike Henry
Hey, Mike Henry!
我們想你 加油
Miss you, man! Keep fighting!
不止他在想你 我們都想你 Mike
He's not the only one who misses you, Mike. We all do.
你該回來工作
You should come back to work.
拜托 你忘了我為啥離開嗎
Come on. Are you forgetting why I left?
你還記得那個輪椅事故嗎
Do you remember the rolling chair thing?
如果你老是想著最壞的情況
If you spend your time worrying about the worst-case scenario
等它真的發生了 就等于經歷了兩次
and it actually happens, you've lived it twice.
伴隨著這 我與你們道別 和這十一年來
And with that, I leave you the same way I have
每晚的告別方式一樣
every night for the last 11 years:
關注時事 紐約 接下來是晚間新聞
Stay informed, New York. Nightly news is next.
好吧 你看上去好多了啊
Well, you seem better.
而且 我們現在有個叫輪子鎖的東西了
Plus we have these little things called wheel locks now.
Harris 我不想得到一份靠別人同情的工作
Look, Harris, I don't want a pity job.
我們都知道如果我回來
We both know if I come back,
NBC會靠展示我的緩慢動作
NBC's going to milk it by showing me in slow motion
和蹩腳的勵志背景音樂來賺錢
with lame uplifting music in the background.
只要我還是新聞主管 這就不可能發生
As long as I'm the news director, that will not happen.
不過你的想法挺好的嘛 拜托 考慮一下吧
It's a good idea, though. Come on. Just think about it.
我們需要你啊 都沒人看新聞了
We need you, man. No one's watching the news anymore.
我們昨晚收視率輸給個叫"顏色飛濺"的節目
We got beat by a show called "Color splash" Last night.
那節目就是看著顏料變干啊
That's literally watching paint dry.
Mike Henry 你是個勇敢的人
Mike Henry. You're a brave man.
我奶奶也有帕金森綜合癥
My grandma has Parkinson's.
是的 我爸爸是個名人 大家都喜歡他
Yes, my Dad is a celebrity, and people love him.
之類的
Blah, blah, blah.
但是大家干嘛要停下來告訴他
But why does everyone have to stop and tell him
關于另一個人也得帕金森的事呢
about another person who also has Parkinson's?
酗酒也是一種病啊
Alcoholism is a disease.
怎么就沒人去跟David Hasselhoff說
Do people go up to David Hasselhoff
因酗酒而得了癲癇的著名演員
他們瘋子叔叔的酗酒故事呢
and tell him about their crazy uncles?
好了同學們 安靜
All right, guys, settle down.
<憤怒的葡萄>看的怎么樣了
Grapes of wrath updates:
<憤怒的葡萄> 描寫美國三十年代經濟恐慌期間大批農民破產逃荒的故事
Eve 怎么樣了 不錯 挺好的 多謝關心
Eve, how's it going? - Good. Really good, thanks.
- 你呢 - 挺好 謝謝
- How are you? - I'm good. Thanks.
- 請告訴我你已經開始做了 - 當然了
- Please tell me you started your project. - Of course I have.
我打算拍個家庭錄像 Henry一家
I am doing a video on another family: The Henrys.
我覺得如果我能
I just think that if I could compare
把我爸與病魔的斗爭與移民勞工做比較
my father's struggles to that of the migrant laborers,
肯定很能傳播正能量
that could really go a long way with the healing.
- 聽上去不錯 周四前交 - 在<憤怒的葡萄>這本小說里
- Sounds good. Due Thursday. - In the grapes of wrath,
喬德和他爸媽逃離了危險區
Ma and Pa Joad escape the dust bowl.
我爸爸的病就是我們家的危險區
My Dad's condition is the dust bowl of my family,
而我們就是葡萄
and we are the grapes...
等等 我們是葡萄還是憤怒呢
Wait, are we the grapes, or are we the wrath?
- 啊 誰能給... - 安靜點 我正在工作呢
- Ah, who gives a... - Quiet! I'm trying to work in here.
你才安靜點
You be quiet.
如果要說帕金森教會我什么
If Parkinson's has taught me anything,
它讓我知道你不能掌控一切
it's that you can't control everything.
最后那次新聞嗎
Last newscast?
是 現在他們在前面加了個艾力達(偉哥)的廣告
Yeah, they run a Levitra ad in front of it now.
- 艾力達是什么 - 你不知道真好
- What's Levitra? - I so love that you don't know.
- 稍后是夜間新聞 - 完美收官
- Nightly news is next. - And he sticks the landing!
你跟Harris說你一定不會回去工作嗎
So you told Harris that you are definitely not going back?
回去了也只是一個勵志角色
I mean, I'd just be a feel-good story to them.
我不想干份每天上班大家都
I don't want to be the guy who gets a standing ovation
- 起立鼓掌的工作 - 起立鼓掌
- every day at work. - Standing ovations?
- 這幫混蛋 - 你懂我的意思
- Ugh, those sons of bitches. - You know what I'm saying.
我只是 覺得你
I just... I feel like you've
最近有點精神緊張
been a little intense around here lately,
就這樣 采蘋果啦 樹葉大戰啦
that's all. The apple picking, leaf fights?
我不喜歡樹葉大戰 我又不是小浣熊
I don't like leaf fights. I'm not a raccoon.
當我離開職場 我覺得唯一的好處就是
When I left work, I thought the silver lining
有了更多的時間陪你和孩子
was that I'd get to spend more time with you and the kids,
但是你們都在忙各自的事情
but now you all have your own things going on.
我正好有事讓你做
I have just the fix for you.
明天十一點到下午六點你得在家
You have to be here tomorrow between 11:00 and 6:00.
我們要個新的洗碗機 舊的被Graham弄壞了
We need a new dishwasher because Graham broke ours.
- Graham - 你只要幫他們開個門就好
- Graham. - All you have to do is let them in.
確定他們把主水管管道
And make sure that they connect the main water line
連上過濾管道 對了 這樣吧
to the filter line, and... you know what?
- 我給你留張便條 - 你知道我討厭這活
- Hey, I'll leave you a note. - You know I hate this stuff.
明天我還要繼續忙我的書
I was going to go work on my book tomorrow.
好吧 讓我來彌補你一下
Well, I can make it up to you.
你上次吃藥是什么時候
When was the last time you took your medication?
- 幾小時以前吧 - 哦 很好
- Hours ago. - Oh, good.
那我能省點力了
Then I don't have to do all the work.
我不知道 感覺留劉海的都是胖子
I don't know; it feels like bangs are for heavy people.
去年夏天我留過劉海
I had bangs last summer.
好吧 你就是規則的例外
Well, you're the exception that proves the rule,
不過夏天總是你的"大"季節
although summer is always your biggest season,
- 如果坦白說的話 - 真是多謝你了
- if I'm just being real. - Thanks for that.
這就是為什么我今天不能寫作嗎 這樣你就可以照看發型
Is this why I can't go write today? So you can babysit a haircut?
這不只是什么發型 Michael
It's not just some haircut, Michael.
這表明了我的歲數
It's a symbol of my mortality.
在演唱會上 總有一些傻瓜真的以為
At the concert, some idiot actually thought
我老得可以做Eve的媽媽
that I was old enough to be Eve's mom.
這些傻瓜長眼睛 耳朵了嗎
Does this idiot have eyes, ears,
還是他們解讀信息能力不足啊
and the ability to process information?
我知道 你很難撇開自己順遂的人生
I know it's hard for you to step outside your charmed life
直視他人生活中的挑戰
and see other people's challenges,
但我這都要奔四了啊
but I'm about to turn 30-FF-nna.
我體內的卵子(也指"蛋")比班尼根西餐店都少
I have less eggs inside me than a Bennigan's
那兒根本不賣早餐
because they don't serve breakfast!
Michael 你有在聽嗎
Michael, are you even listening to me?
哦 沒有 說到班尼根那兒就走神了
Oh, no. You lost me at Bennigan's.
貌似是班尼根出了啥事
Whatever happened to Bennigan's?
Mike是個慷慨的哥哥 某種意義上來說
Mike's a generous big brother... to a point.
比如 他給我這樓里租了一間公寓
Like, he helps me pay rent on an apartment in the building,
不過是地下室 窗戶都不透光
but it's in the basement. These windows don't let any light in,
但卻有混混能看到我裸體走來走去
but scumbags can watch me walk around naked.
那你為啥不關上百葉窗
Why don't you close the blinds?
因為這些混混里可能有醫生
Because one of those scumbags might be a doctor.
Mike Henry 4頻道的新聞節目
Mike Henry! News on Channel 4!
- 關注時"四" - 洗碗機
- Stay informs! - Dishwasher!
- Mike Henry - 對 是我 洗碗機
- Mike Henry! - Right, Mike Henry. Dishwasher.
就是這兒
This is the place.
在哪兒呢 在這兒
Where is this thing? Oh, here it is.
好 "接上肉汁"
Oh, great. "Connect the gravy..."
- 為什么說肉汁 - 看來沒用
- Why would it say "Gravy"? - This is not gonna be helpful.
知道我要怎么做嗎 我給我妻子打個電話
So you know what I'll do? I'll call my wife on her cell phone,
然后她就會把事情都辦妥
and she will straighten this whole thing out.
那是我的皮博迪獎杯
That's my peabody award.
皮博迪獎 表彰那些在電子媒介（包括廣播、電視以及有線電視）方面的杰出成就
911 你有什么緊急情況
911. What is your emergency?
911 我沒打911啊 沒什么緊急情況
911? No, I didn't call 911. No, there's no emergency.
你知道嗎 我是要打917 結果打錯了
You know what I did? I called 917 but I misdialed.
我的藥還沒起效
My drugs haven't kicked in.
drug還有毒品之意
我很好 我很好 喂
I'm fine. I'm fine! Hello?
我放棄了 我不知道是哪個
I give up! I don't know which one it is.
我放棄 我放棄 我放棄
I give up. I give up. I give up.
- 后退 - 舉起手來
- Back away! - Hands up!
- 警察 - 沒事 沒事 我很好
- N.Y.P.D.! - Nyet! Nyet! Nyet! I'm fine!
我電話上說了我沒事
I said I was fine on the phone!
這不重要 我們總得有回應
Doesn't matter. We have to respond.
- 現在道歉總比你出事好 - 我45分鐘前打的電話
- Better safe than sorry. - You know, I called 45 minutes ago.
要是這真是一個緊急事件
If this were a real emergency,
你現在妥妥得道歉了
it'd fall squarely in the "Sorry" Category.
不是我們的錯 是新的911呼叫系統
It's not us. It's the new 911 call system.
花了20億就這玩意兒
That's what you get for $2 billion.
- 20億 - 我們明天再來
- $2 billion? - We'll just come back tomorrow.
- 十一點到下午"性"點 - 等等 我給你們
- Between 11:00 and 6:00. - Wait, I get...
- 關注時"四" - 關注時"四" 事啦
- Stay informs! - Stay informs... informed!
他剛剛說的是"性"嗎
Did he say "Sex?"
對 Harris 是我 Mike 我想了想你的提議
Yeah, Harris. It's Mike. I been thinking about your offer.
你那還有輪子鎖吧
You still got those wheel locks?
打擾一下 Henry先生 既然我都來了
Excuse me, Mr. Henry. Since we're both here,
能給簽個名嗎 我舅舅得了老年癡呆
could I get you to sign an autograph? My uncle's got Alzheimer's.
- 我得的是帕金森 - 差不多
- I've actually got Parkinson's. - Either way.
Harris 我必須回去工作
Harris, I got to get back to work.
不知道 就是感覺輕了了許多
I don't know. I just feel lighter, you know?
精神上肉體上 我不想看起來顯得太年輕
Emotionally and physically. I don't want to look too young.
你剪頭發了 看起來完全一樣啊
You got a haircut? It looks exactly the same.
你怎么會嫁給他 他有夸過你漂亮嗎
How did you marry him? Does he ever tell you you're pretty?
Ian 進來 晚飯時間
Ian, come in here! It's dinner time.
好 再來一遍 但是要說 "Ian 我需要幫助"
Okay, do that again, But say "Ian, I need help!"
晃得再厲害些
And shake it up a little.
你太壞了 就是一壞女兒
You're garbage. You're a garbage daughter.
好了 鑒于你們都在這里 我有事要宣布
Good, we're all here. I got an announcement I want to make.
我不想惹你們生氣 或是困惑 害怕
I don't want you to get angry or confused or scared,
但是 我在考慮回去工作
but I'm... thinking about going back to work.
- 哦 - 謝天謝地
- Oh! - Thank god!
- 太棒了 - 我是說我在考慮
- Yes! - I said I was thinking about it.
- 真高興知道你們什么立場 - 我們只是有點
- Good to know where I stand. - We're just kind of happy
- 高興你終于走出房門 - 有點而已嗎
- that you're getting out of the house. - Kind of?
你最近都快把我們逼瘋了
You've been driving us all a little crazy lately.
啥 太扯了
What? That's nuts.
好啦 該死 不能再這樣了
All right, damn it! That's not happening again!
吐出來 吐出來 別再站著吃飯了
Spit that out. Spit that out. No more standing meals.
我告訴你 會出問題的
I'm telling you. This is gonna happen.
夠了 你別再這樣了 他都八歲了 Mike
Okay, you have got to stop that. He is eight years old, Mike.
就因為他不在餐桌上吃飯
'Cause he's not eating at a family table.
你來了啊 歡迎回來 朋友
Ha! There he is! Welcome home, my friend.
- 這只是考察會面 - 哦 當然
- This is an exploratory meeting. - Oh, of course.
都沒人知道你來了 來吧
No one knows you're here. Come on.
我說謊了 他們愛死你了 伙計
I lied. They love you, man.
- 人人都愛你 - 你個壞人
- The whole world loves you. - You're a bad man.
歡迎回來 Henry先生 我是Kay 你的新任節段制片人
Welcome back, Mr. Henry. I'm Kay, your new segment producer.
- 有可能是我新任節段制片人 - 對 我得努力爭取
- Potential new segment producer. - Right. I've got to earn it.
我會的 因為 成為這個的一份子 你的一部分
And I will. Because to be a part of this... A part of you...
- 激勵他人是... - 你在哭嗎 她在哭嗎
- to call it inspirational is... - Are you crying? Is she crying?
你要是不喜歡她 我立馬換了她
If you don't like her, I can drop her like a stone.
不 我喜歡她比我矮 感覺不錯
No, I like that she's shorter than me. It's a nice touch.
看看你 你狀態已經回來了
Look at you. You're back already.
這是舊的控制室
And here's the old control room.
Mike Henry 風云人物來了啊
Mike Henry. There's the man of the hour.
Matthew
Matthew.
Matt Lauer和我老是較勁
Matt Lauer and I have always had a rivalry.
我們一起提拔上來的 只有一個人還有秀發
We both came up together. One of us still has his hair.
只是單方面的充滿嫉妒的較勁
It's a one-sided rivalry fueled by jealousy.
- 嫉妒 - 我剛看到你的回歸廣告了
- Jealousy? - I just saw your welcome back promo.
你回來真是太好了 你可是頂尖的
I couldn't be happier. You are one of the best.
- 嘿 謝謝 伙計 - 稍后跑道見
- Well, thanks, man. - See you at the track later?
好 待會見
Yeah, I'll see you there.
- 這家伙真神奇 - 超級糟糕的男人
- Can you believe that guy? - Awful, awful man.
為什么大家都沒看到這點...
Why don't people see that...
等等 什么廣告
Wait a minute. What do you mean "Promo?
好啦 這樣的
All right, fine.
我就知道你會回來的
I was straight-up assuming you were coming back.
我在街上見到你 像個男保姆似的 真傷感
I saw you in the street, mannying your kids. It was sad.
男保姆 那叫親子關系 Harris
"Mannying?" It's called parenthood, Harris.
大部分男人還是在追求這個的
And most men don't spend their lives trying to avoid it.
專注性愛三十年 沒搞大過一個
Hey, 30 years of lovemaking, not even one slip.
- 差點搞大都沒有 - 也許你用錯方法了
- Not even a scare. - Maybe you're doing it wrong.
不就是這樣嗎
It's like this, right?
凡事皆出有因 Mike
Some things happen for a reason, Mike,
正如我們在Goldfarb偶遇
like us running into each other at Goldfarb's.
都是注定的 你注定就是做新聞的 Mike
It was fate. News is in your blood, Mike.
拜托 你和我們是分不開的
Come on, you need us just as much as we need you.
其實我生活挺美滿的
Actually, I've got a rather full life.
我們這周末全家人要去摘蘋果
The whole family's going apple picking this weekend.
看 還是你以前的主播椅哦
Ooh! It's your old anchor chair.
快來坐坐看
Come on, give it a spin.
Harris 我們就別再玩猜啞謎了吧
Harris, can we just stop with this whole charade?
啞謎 什么啞謎
Charade? What charade?
我沒有在玩啊 我有點累了 然后呢
I don't play charades, man. I'm a little tired. So what?
坐一下 噢 新的輪鎖
I sit down. Ooh, new wheel locks.
我有動嗎 紋絲不動
Am I moving? Mm! Not an inch.
想伸手拿支筆 夠不著
You reach for a pen, nothing.
想分析下圖表 夠不著 想看看天氣 噢 卡住了
Point to a graph, nothing. Throw it to weather, locked in.
如果我們每天都能在這吃早餐就好了
Please say we can always eat breakfast here.
如果爸爸以后像今天一樣早起上班
If Dad starts going into work early like this,
- 當然可以 - 我覺得這樣對他也好
- yes, we can. - I think it's the best thing for him.
我都帶著電腦到咖啡店了 像個流浪漢似的
All right, I'm bringing my laptop to a panera like a drifter.
- 你會問 為什么呢 - 我懂
- Why, you ask? - I know.
因為我不能在一個改裝壁櫥里過下去了
Because I can't live/work in a converted closet!
我睡在嬰兒床上啊 媽 Eve還在隔壁
I sleep in a baby's bed, mom! Eve's next door,
- 用垃圾音樂轟炸我耳膜 - 你不也喜歡魔力紅嗎
- blasting her garbage music... - You like Maroon 5.
我喜歡的是Adam Levine 他是個會講故事的歌手
I like Adam Levine! He's a storyteller.
魔力紅主唱
認輸吧
Just accept it.
把我以前的房間還給我
Give me back my old room back,
或者我睡你的工藝室
or let me take over your crafting room.
- 那我去哪做手工 - 你都多久沒碰了
- Where would I craft? - When's the last time you crafted?
我的愛好可不是站在這受審 我愛手工藝
My hobbies are not on trial here. I love crafting.
至少 我該愛手工藝
At least, I'm supposed to love crafting.
八卦雜志都這么說的
That's what all those bitchy magazines say.
- 媽 - 自從你輟學
- Mom... - When you left for college,
就已經放棄居住的所有權利了
you renounced all rights of habitation.
作為家里真正意義上的小孩
As a child who actually belongs in our home,
- 只有Graham有這個權利 - 我給你一成我公司的股份
- Graham has dibs. - Hey, I'll give you 10% of my company.
心領了
No thanks.
你就不該付他松餅的錢
You really shouldn't even be paying for his muffin.
- 要我我就會自立 - 好了 你先別說
- I'd cut the cord. - Okay, you don't talk.
聽說你以做課堂展示為由拿走了臺電視
I heard you signed out a TV for your presentation.
你怎么花言巧語讓Diaz先生讓你這么干了
What sort of nonsense did you con Mr. Diaz into letting you do?
教師與學生間的保密協議呢
Whatever happened to teacher/student confidentiality?
根本沒有這么一說 永遠都沒這一說
That's not a thing. That will never be a thing.
你的回巢之作
Your first segment should be a return
應該與你之前的著名形象相呼應
to the kind of reporting you were famous for:
在街頭游蕩
Out on the street, hustling,
總能挖到好新聞的男人
the guy who always finds the story.
你想做什么類型的新聞都行 Mike
You can do any story you like, Mike.
關于政治或者關于動物園里的熊貓
Like politics or a panda at the ZOO
又或者自己如何自強不息
or overcoming personal obstacles.
嘿 我喜歡這個 自強不息
Hey, I like that one: Overcoming personal obstacles.
- 就做這個吧 - Harris 如果我真回來了
- I'd do that one. - Harris, if I did come back,
我是回來工作的 不是來推銷的
it would be for the work, not the exploitation.
我才不會叫你那么做呢
I wouldn't have it any other way.
美國人最喜愛的新聞工作者回來了
America's favorite newsman is back.
噢 有沒有搞錯...
Oh, for the love of...
Mike Henry回歸NBC 4 他準備好了 你呢
Mike Henry returns to NBC 4. He's ready. Are you?
- 夠了 我走了 - 嘿 Mike Henry
- That's it. I'm out of here. - Oh, come... Mike Henry.
給點掌聲 各位
Come on. Come on, everybody.
Mike Henry 收視的保證
Mike Henry! Guaranteed ratings.
收視的保證
Guaranteed ratings.
盡管我爸一生中歷經那么多的不幸
Although my Dad has experienced enormous tragedy in his life...
早上能自己穿上褲子已經很了不起了
just putting his pants on every morning is a gift...
他仍迎難而上
he bravely soldiers on,
他是位英雄
and that makes him a hero.
Eve 你留一下
Uh, Eve, hang back a sec.
編輯得真不錯 那個漸變
Great job editing that together. Those wipe transitions:
就是看著一個畫面
I mean, you'd be looking at one thing,
然后畫面慢慢剝落
and then it would just peel away
接著轉換到下一個畫面
and then you'd be looking at something else.
- 太棒了 - 我只是個信息傳播者
- Wow. - I'm just the messenger.
- 你不及格 - 什么
- I'm failing you. - What?
這都是你憑空堆砌出來的
The whole thing was manipulative,
這根本和<憤怒的葡萄>沒聯系
and you made no connection to the grapes of wrath.
- 我們就是現實版窮苦求職者 - 今天你本有機會在這
- I called us the modern-day okies... - You had a chance here
反映你家的真實狀況
to really reflect on your family,
有關你爸的經歷
on what your Dad's been through,
你的經歷 而你卻只是拿著手機胡亂拍拍
what you've been through, but instead you just held up a phone.
這些都是扯淡
That was a puff piece.
- 不是這樣的 - 可能我看錯你了
- I beg to differ. - Maybe I was wrong about this whole
還以為你是個聰明的女生 能用自己的實例做出精彩的演示
smart-girl-who-could-be-amazing- if-she-applied-herself thing,
因為若你足夠聰明
because if you were really bright,
你就知道此時就該這么做
you'd know now's the time to apply yourself.
"你的肌膚如黎明色 我的彌漫著麝香"
"Your skin like dawn. Mine like musk."
- 你說的對 這些詩句糟糕透了 - 這是馬婭·安杰盧寫的
- You're right. This poetry's terrible. - That's Maya Angelou.
婭·安杰盧 美國作家和詩人
腦補了大詩人的聲音后 這詩真是太美了
Oh, now that I hear it in her voice, it's breathtaking.
- 你的會議開得怎樣 - 糟糕透了
- How was your meeting? - Awful.
他們甚至已經給我剪輯了個慢鏡頭廣告
They already cut together a promo showing me in slow-motion.
- 所以呢 - 如果你出現在慢鏡頭里
- So? - When they show you in slow-motion,
要不就是你死了 要不被起訴了
you're either dead or under indictment.
還有可能是在美國偶像淘汰了
Or you just got kicked off of American Idol.
美帝歌唱類選秀節目
看來你今天過得不怎樣啊
You had a bad day.
我覺得我更像是可憐蟲Mike
I think just think of me as "Mike the poor son-of-a-bitch,"
而不是新聞人Mike
not "Mike the newsman."
我就不該去的
I never should've gone down there.
你怎么不說話
You're not saying anything.
我覺得不止是那個廣告嚇到你了
I think it's not just a promo that's scaring you off.
那是直播 你沒有信心能做好
It's live TV: You're not sure if you can do it anymore.
如果我不再是他們心目中那個人了呢
What if I'm not the guy they remember?
你不會是的 當然有所不同
You won't be. You'll be different.
可你還是你
But you'll still be you.
你可是那個說要放棄掌控權的人
Aren't you the guy who talked about giving up control?
你以為每次我遇到困難
You think every time I get in a tough situation
你只要這樣就能讓情況變好嗎
you can make it better by just...
- 你摸到奶頭了 Eve 我們走了 - 走
- That's a nipple. Eve, we got to go. - Let's go.
去屋頂嗎
Roof?
用避孕套玩這個很奇怪
It's weird using condoms.
是啊 在學校他們就像派糖果一樣派發
Yeah, they give these out like candy in college.
你知道嗎 拿著500個免費的
You know, getting 500 free
避孕套沒有保護到我 反而覺得很有壓力
condoms isn't preventative; it's pressure.
竟然沒有破 太失望了
It sucks they don't break.
你該感到安心
You're meant to take comfort in that.
Diaz沒讓我及格 那個視頻 他就差沒直接說我虛偽了
Diaz failed me. For that video. He basically called me a phony.
讓他再給你次機會
So ask him for an incomplete.
告訴他你要證明他是錯的 Diaz就喜歡這種扯淡
Tell him you want to prove him wrong... Diaz loves that crap...
然后繼續用心做這個課題
Then just keep working on the
直到自己滿意
project till you're proud of what you've got.
那我要再多拍你一點
But then I'll have to film you a lot more.
掛就掛了吧 你就是虛偽
Take the "F." You're a phony.
我為什么要跟你談這個呢 你個全A生
Why am I talking to you about this? You got straight As.
人無完人 我并不是僅僅因為
I'm not perfect. Starting you-search.Net
要做"從你開始搜索"網站而回來的
Isn't the only reason why I'm back here.
- 這個網站到底怎么找 - 去谷歌一下
- Yeah, how do I find that again? - Just Google it.
好吧 等等 想要用你的搜索引擎
Uh, okay, wait. To get to your search engine,
我先要用別的搜索引擎搜索嗎
I have to use another search engine?
上學期我經濟學也不及格
I failed Econ last semester.
按照正態曲線給分
It was graded on a curve,
很明顯康奈爾大學所有人都比我聰明
and apparently everyone at Cornell is smarter than me.
噢 爸媽知道嗎
Whoa. Do Mom and Dad know?
- 求你別告訴他們 - 不會的
- Please don't tell them. - Why would I?
這是個非常嚴峻的內部問題
That's actually a serious internal question.
我得想想要勒索你什么
I'll figure out what I want to blackmail you for
再來找你
and then get back to you.
- 砸到一個老女人 - 那是Leigh姑姑
- Nailed an old lady. - That's aunt Leigh.
- Kay 我是Mike 我回來了 - 什么
- Kay, it's Mike. I'm back in. - What?
我是個總能挖新聞的男人 對吧
Well, I'm the guy who always finds the story, right?
我們必須在一個小時內趕到市政廳
We got to be at city hall in an hour.
但是我還在139街呢
But I'm at 139th street,
我也沒事先叫上采訪車和工作人員啊
and I didn't reserve a news van or a crew.
現在我得找到個能趕到的編輯
Now I've got to find an editor who will crash this last-minute
不是你的問題 不是你的問題
and... not your problem. Not your problem.
真對不起Henry先生
I am so sorry, Mr. Henry.
只是 你真是我的英雄 不管是工作上
It's just, you're a hero of mine, both professionally and...
- 還是電視上 - 聽著 沒事的
- televisionally, and... - Listen, it should be okay.
如果有女人能在樹上生孩子 我們也能處理好這事
If a lady can have a baby in a tree, we can handle this.
什么
What?
這個故事Mike跟我們講過無數遍了
Mike's told us all the same story a thousand times:
在莫桑比克有個孕婦
There was a pregnant woman in Mozambique...
在她產子的那天 她的村子被水淹了
the day she went into labor, her village flooded.
就在她快被水沖走的時候
As she was literally being taken away by the currents...
她爬上了一棵樹 并生下了孩子
she climbed up a tree and gave birth.
她和她的孩子一起在樹上待著
And she stayed in that tree with her newborn
直到她們獲救了
until she was rescued.
所以說不管現在情況多糟
So however bad you think you've got it,
還有女人在樹上生孩子呢
A lady had a baby in a tree.
開始吧
Let's hit it.
我來開門 算了
Let me get the door. Never mind.
- 你怎么跑的比我還快 - 不費吹灰之力
- How are you beating me? - With one brain tied behind my back!
- 你在干什么 - Rocky啊 你多大了
- What are you doing? - Rocky. How old are you?
史泰龍主演電影<洛奇>中拳擊手洛奇的經典動作
議員先生
Look, Councilman,
你給解釋一下怎么20億美元都沒能升級911報警系統
either you explain to me how $2 billion fails to upgrade 911
不然我的下一個電話就打給電子系統部門
or my next call will be to digital systems,
你的小舅子Gerald
where I believe your brother-in-law, Gerald,
好像是那董事會的吧 話筒是開的
is on the board. It's on.
911報警 西4街和13街交叉口發生火災
911 dispatch. Fire on the corner of west 4th and 13th.
- 來吧 - 你就這么讓帽子這么...
- Let's boogie. - You just gonna let it sit like...
- 怎么了 不就一帽子嗎 - 好吧
- What? It's a hat. - Okay. Yes.
- 暈車是么 - 我沒事
- Car sick, huh? - I'm... I'm fine.
對我來說 這里非常平穩
For me, this is perfectly still.
是的 我們剛搞定
Yeah, we just wrapped.
48分鐘了 他們都沒趕到
Yeah, they didn't get here for 48 minutes.
一個電話要花這么久才能有反應
That's how long it took for the call to go through.
還拍到了個救貓咪的消防員
And we got a fireman saving a kitten,
- 接招吧 "顏色飛濺" - 貓咪 太贊了
- so take that, color splash. - A kitty cat? Ah, that's awesome.
Harris 我告訴你 你是對的
Harris, I got to tell you. You were right.
重出江湖的感覺真棒
It feels great to be back out here again.
我的意思是 我從來沒感覺這么好
I mean, I never felt better.
那你肯定會喜歡這個的
Well, you're going to love this then.
你能在"今日秀"里介紹你的部分 直播噢
They want you to introduce your segment on the today show, Live.
NBC某檔節目
- 首次熒幕回歸 就上全國直播了 - 你講真的
- First time out, and you're goin' national. - Are you serious?
是的 Matt Lauer欽點的你
Yes, matt Lauer requested you personally.
"今日秀"的骨灰級王牌主播
那家伙可不得了
That guy's aces.
不能讓你慢慢適應了 這是大動作了 對吧
So much for easing back in. This is big boy stuff, right?
Mike
Mike?
那是Mike Henry 我的私交
It's Mike Henry. Personal friend.
得了帕金森 真是可惜 可他是個斗士
Parkinson's. Aw, so sad, but he's a fighter.
你實習的怎么樣了
How's that internship doing?
相比于嘔吐我更喜歡哭
I like crying better than puking.
我在控制吃藥的時間 保證不會發作
I'm trying to time my meds so they kick in just before I go on.
嗨 能比在樹上生孩子難嗎
Hey, lady had a baby in a tree.
是的 她做到了
Yes, she did.
我們今天有一位特別嘉賓回歸了
And we're back with a very special guest this morning.
他就是Mike Henry
Mike Henry is here.
新聞主播 Mike Henry
攜爆炸性新聞回歸熒屏
能和老朋友在一塊真好
It's always good to be with old friends.
就好像你從來沒離開過一樣
It feels like you never left.
你上去在健康狀況的巔峰啊
You look like you're in the pinnacle of health.
- 巔峰是不敢說啦 - 現在看看外場Al那兒的狀況
- I wouldn't say pinnacle. - Let's go outside to Al right now.
Al 外面反應怎么樣 大家都喜歡這家伙嗎
Al, what's the reaction out there? Anybody like this guy?
Matt 我告訴你 貌似整個紐約
Matt, I got to tell you, seems like the whole city turned out
都出來迎接他們的主播了
to welcome back their anchor.
你們對Mike Henry歸來怎么看
What do you guys think about Mike Henry coming back?
看看外面激動的人群 我好多年沒看到這樣的場景了
Look at the excitement out there. I haven't seen this in years.
自從"超級減肥王"來了后就沒見過這樣的了
I haven't seen it since the biggest loser was here.
NBC一檔減肥真人秀節目
- 他回來真好 是吧 - 我才花了6個月
- Good to see him back, huh? - Only took six months to figure out
就想出怎么讓他和你在Goldfarb偶遇
how to get him to run into you at Goldfarb's.
我和新一代黑人一樣喜歡白鮭魚
I mean, I like whitefish just as much as the next black man,
但是那里弄的也太糟了
but it got a little farkakt.
我還是不懂為啥不直接讓我給他打電話
I still don't know why you didn't just have me call him.
Mike你知道的 他喜歡自己拿主意
You know Mike. It had to be his idea.
- 所以他不知道這一切 - 不知道
- So he has no clue? - No.
- 他也不知道我們的事 - 別拿這開玩笑好么
- He doesn't know about us either. - Hey, don't joke about that.
- 我是說你給我開了一扇窗 - 夠了
- I mean, you give me a window... - Okay.
在他的回歸首秀
In his first segment back,
Mike盯上了市政府高昂的
Mike took on the city's costly overhaul
報警系統更新
of the emergency call system.
是的Matt 那可是個大新聞
That's right, Matt. It's a pretty compelling story,
我很感謝你讓全國觀眾知道了這事兒
and I appreciate you giving it a nationwide audience.
當然要啦 很高興你回來了 Mike
How could we not? It's a thrill to have you back, Mike.
兩天前 我誤播了一次911
Two days ago, I accidentally made a 911...
對不起Mike 我要打斷你了
Mike, I'm sorry. I have to cut you off.
我必須縮短你的部分了 我接到最新消息
I have to cut this short. I'm getting word right now,
我們從華盛頓方面接到爆炸性新聞
we have breaking news out of Washington.
我將衛星聯線
I want to go live via satellite
白宮的Peter Alexander  Peter接手吧
to Peter Alexander at the White House. Peter, take it away.
對不起 Mike
I am so sorry, Mike.
- 你做的很好 - 我真的很抱歉
- You did a great job. - I'm really sorry.
你本該說說自強不息的
You should've done overcoming personal obstacles
或者動物園的熊貓 這種寶可不會被打斷
or at least panda at the ZOO. You don't cut away from that gold.
- 你還好吧 Mike - 沒事 不可能掌控一切
- You all right, Mike? - Hey, yeah. You can't control everything.
除了你 在我老婆旁邊時控制一下自己
Except you. Control yourself around my wife.
不然揍死你
I will take you down.
我是怎么看Mike Henry的
What do I really think about Mike Henry?
他是得過很多獎的主播 也是很棒的爸爸
He was an award-winning news anchor and an awesome Dad,
但是他得了那個該死的病
and then he got a stupid disease.
嘿 正好我們在一塊
Hey, as long as we're together,
我們去吃早飯吧怎么樣
why don't we go get some breakfast?
不了 我去學校前要洗個澡
Nah, I've got to shower before school.
我要評論文 我們還是走吧
I have papers to grade, so we should get going.
好吧 的確不能掌控一切
Well, I guess you really can't control everything.
不行
Nope.
我愛我的家庭
I love my family!
當然他不是過去的那個他了
Of course he's not the same person he used to be.
發生了那么多事 他怎么可能還是原來的他
With everything that's happened, how could he be?
等等 待著別動
Just give me a second! Stay here.
- 嗨 - 這搞什么
- Hey. - What's that all about?
我不知道 她什么都干的出來 誰知道呢
I don't know. Could be anything with her. Who knows?
Harris是個很好的朋友
You know, Harris is a really good friend.
不是為了他 我不會回來工作的
If it wasn't for him, I wouldn't be going back to work.
總是很多因素促成的嘛
Well... There are a lot of reasons why things happen...
不 就只有這個 就是因為Harris
No, it was that one singular reason. It's just Harris.
- 你懂什么 - 都懂
- What do you know? - Everything.
如果我能控制眼神的話 現在就會朝你使眼色
If I could wink on command, I'd wink at you right now.
謝謝你了
Thanks.
好了
Okay!
上帝保佑我們
God help us.
誰把廚房給炸了
Hey, who blew up the kitchen?
大驚喜噢
Surprise!
坐下吃飯 懂了嗎
Sit-down meal. Get it?
- 他們的主意 - 餐桌就是要有
- Their idea. - Well, this is what the dining room table
食物擺上面才有餐桌的樣子嘛
looks like with food on it.
事實上 我們每個人不是過去的自己 我們仍然在不停的改變
The truth is, none of us are the same, and we're still changing.
那是堪比真華夫餅的模型華夫餅
These are the idea of waffles more than actual waffles.
因為我的公寓沒有烤箱
Because I don't have an actual oven in my apartment.
盡管如此 我爸仍不停努力
But through it all, my dad has never stopped trying,
一直在我們身邊 作為這個家庭的一份子
never stopped being here... A part of this family.
這一切都造就了這么棒的他
And that's what makes him amazing.
相比于在樹上生孩子的女士 這算不了啥
If a lady can have a baby in a tree, then this is nothing.
這太好了 這就是我想要的
This is great. This is all I wanted.
誰要雞蛋
Who wants eggs?
這時候就別逞能了好嗎
Can you not have a personal victory right now?
我們餓死了
We are starving.
你能介紹Matt Lauer給我認識么
Do you think you could introduce me to Matt Lauer?
電波字幕組 歡迎您的加入
官方網站:www.dbfansub.com
新浪微博:@電波字幕組